AJUGBA MARIAM EYEWUMI, M.D.

+2347046284438

ajugbamariam@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an ardent medical officer with over 3 years working experience in the clinical sector. Dedicated to exemplary patient outcomes and following all necessary medical procedures with the use of the latest industry equipment and technology.

CORE SKILLS

- Pre-hospital patient care.
- Effective communication skills with patients, patient relatives, and other medical professionals.
- Hospital assessment, diagnosis and treatment of patients.
- Emergency patient care.
- Leadership and managerial skills.

EXPERIENCE

GUARDS BRIGADE MEDICAL CENTRE ASOKORO, ABUJA

Medical Officer

Feb. 2021- Sept. 2021

- Management of over 200 patients with no mortality.
- Conducted 25 successful spontaneous vaginal deliveries.
- Carried out 10 successful episiorrhaphies.
- Carried out 5 successful evacuation of retained product of conception.
- Successfully circumcised 5 male neonates.
- Monitored the management and follow up of 20 post-operative cases.

REKA SPECIALIST HOSPITAL WARRI, DELTA STATE

Medical Officer

May 2020 - Nov. 2020

- As the only Medical Officer, I successfully coordinated the administrative and clinical activities of the hospital within the duration. I was in charge of 15 Staff.
- Assisted 30 caesarean deliveries and 20 gynaecological operations.
- Carried out 30 successful spontaneous vaginal deliveries and 10 successful episiotomies/ episiorraphies.
- Successfully circumcised 10 male neonates.
- Directly involved in the management of over 100 patients with no mortality recorded.

CENTRAL HOSPITAL WARRI, DELTA STATE

House Officer

Dec. 2018 – Dec. 2019

- I was the Assistant Chief House Officer, coordinating the affair of 10 other house officers over a one year period.
- Femoral cannulation of 10 patients for haemodialysis.
- Management and follow up of 30 HIV/AIDS and Tuberculosis patients.
- Management and follow up of 5 cancer patients.
- Cast application and removal in orthopedic surgery.
- Conducted 50 successful spontaneous vaginal deliveries.
- Carried out 40 successful episiorrhaphy and 2 manual evacuation of retained products of conception.

NATIONAL HOSPITAL FCT- ABUJA.

Elective Clinical Posting

May 2017 – June 2017

Elective Clinical Posting in Obstetrics and Gynaecology

• Assisted in the management of 15 Obstetrics & Gynaecology cases.

EDUCATION

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

Doctor of Medicine (M.D)

Jan. 2012-Sept. 2018

Delta State University, Abraka, Nigeria (MBBS 2018).

LICENSES / CERTIFICATES

- 2022 Annual Practicing License.
- Full Registration with the Medical and Dental Council of Nigeria.
- Nigerian Red Cross Society; Competence Based Standard First Aid Course, July 2021.
- Certificate in National Health Care Provider Solutions (NHCPS) Basic Life Support, Postgraduate Institute for Medicine, USA.

- Certificate in NHCPS Advanced Cardiac Life Support, Postgraduate Institute for Medicine, USA.
- Certificate in NHCPS Paediatric Advanced Life Support, Postgraduate Institute for Medicine, USA.
- Certificate in NHCPS Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation/ Automated External Defibrillator/ First Aid, Postgraduate Institute for Medicine, USA.

LEADERSHIP SERVICE

- Chief Medical Officer at REKA Specialist Hospital (May-Nov 2020).
- Assistant Chief House Officer at Central Hospital Warri (December 2018 December 2019).
- Acting President of the Delta State University Medical Students' Association (2017-2018).
- Assistant Class Coordinator (Jan.2017 Sept. 2018).
- Vice- President of the Delta State University Medical Students' Association (2016-2017).
- Assistant Sports Director, Nigeria Medical Students' Association (NIMSA) Games, Delta State chapter (2016).
- Secretary of the Delta State University Medical Students' Association (2014 -2015).
- Physics Laboratory Prefect (Sept. 2009 -June 2010).

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

- Sensitization Campaign on Mental Health and Cholera Outbreak by the NYSC Red Cross CDS Group, Garki, Abuja (August, 2021).
- Creative thinking, Mental Health Education and Sex Education to about 200 children within ages 7-17 years at the IDP Camp David, Durumi, Abuja (August 2021).
- Medical Outreach in commemoration of the Nigerian Army Day Celebration, Mabushi, Abuja.Medical care was rendered to over 500 people (July 2021).
- Christian Medical and Dental Association of Nigeria (CMDA) Medical Outreach, Lugbe, Abuja.Medical care was rendered to about 100 people (April 2021).
- Health Initiative for Rural Dwellers, Nyanya, Abuja. The programme was attended by about 100 people who received medical care and some relief materials (March 2021).
- Free Medical Care in Warri for over 500 people. October (2020).
- Sensitization of Primary School Children on Personal Hygiene and supply of stationaries, Obiaruku, Delta State (2017).
- CMDA Medical Outreach in Koko Community, Delta State (2016).
- Roll Back Malaria Initiative, Akoko -uno, Delta State (2015).
- Reproductive Health and Family Planning, Igbuku, Delta state (2014).
- CMDA Medical Outreach, Oviri Olomoro Community, Delta State (2012).

SEMINARS / CONFERENCES

- The Business of Medicine and Improving the Earning Capacity of Young Doctors in Abuja by NMA-FCT (October 2021).
- Basic Ultrasound Training by V- Imaging Consult in Collaboration with Guards Brigade Medical Centre, Asokoro, Abuja (August 2021).
- La Buena Vida Entrepreneurship Seminar (July 2020).
- CMDA Western Zonal Prayer and Missions Conference, Delta State University, Abraka (2017).
- Nigeria Medical Students' Association (NIMSA) Games, University of Benin (March 2016).
- CMDA National Conference, Imo State University (2014).
- CMDA Western Zonal Prayer and Missions Conference, Songhai Delta (2013).
- CMDA National Conference, Calabar (2012).
- CMDA PAN-African Conference, Covenant University (2012).

RESEARCH / PUBLICATION

• Cost of Child Health Care in Delta State University Teaching Hospital.

REFERENCES

Dr Emmanuel Akpo

MBBS, DMAS, FMCS, FICS, FUrol, FACS

Deputy Chairman, Medical Advisory Committee

Delta State University Teaching Hospital, Oghara, Delta State.

Telephone: +234 813 516 2418

Colonel OO Ojo

Commanding Officer,

Guards Brigade Medical Center, Asokoro, Abuja.

Telephone: +234 803 715 5629